Guide to the George A. Chauncey Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
George A. Chauncey Papers
1948-2011
RG 267
Yale University Divinity School Library
12
31 boxes
Correspondence, writings, sermons, and collected material document the life and work of George A. Chauncey, who graduated from Yale Divinity School in 1952 and served as a Presbyterian parish minister in the South, activist for civil rights and peace, and founding director of the Washington Office of the Presbyterian Church.
Chauncey, George A., 1927-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of George A. Chauncey, Jr., 2015
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
George A. Chauncey (1927-) is a retired Presbyterian minister who worked for racial justice while serving as pastor of local churches in Tennessee, Arkansas, and Kentucky at the height of the civil rights era from 1952-1965 and worked on civil rights, peace, and global hunger issues after joining the national staff of the Presbyterian Church (US) in 1965.
Born in Memphis, Tennessee, in 1927, Chauncey served with the US Army Counter-Intelligence Corps in post-war Japan before earning his BA degree with honors from Rhodes College in 1949, his M.Div. degree cum laude from Yale Divinity School in 1952, and his D. Min. degree from Union Theological Seminary of Virginia in 1972. In 1952 he married Barbara Leigh Davis, the daughter of Congressman Clifford Davis of Memphis, and was also ordained a Presbyterian minister and called to serve the First Presbyterian Church in Brownsville, Tennessee.
From 1954-58, he served as pastor of a church in Monticello, Arkansas. His papers illustrate the struggles over civil rights in deeply divided southern white churches. In 1954, he was asked to leave his Brownsville pulpit after preaching in support of the Supreme Court's Brown v. Board of Education decision. In 1956, he received both critical and supportive letters from across the South after withdrawing from the University of Mississippi's Religious Emphasis Week after it, under pressure from the state legislature, rescinded the invitation of another speaker discovered to be a (white) member of the NAACP, and, in 1957, he was one of the white ministers who escorted the black students integrating Little Rock's Central High School through hostile mobs. After serving for two years in the Church's Office of Evangelism, he served from 1960-65 as pastor of the First Presbyterian Church in Danville, Kentucky, where he founded the town's Human Relations Council.
In 1965, he joined the denomination's Office of Church and Society in Richmond, Virginia, where he worked primarily in support of civil rights and spent much of his first year travelling the South to advise and support clergy whose support for civil rights had alienated their parishioners. He also chaired the Richmond Mobilization Committee Against the War in Vietnam (1969-70) and the local George McGovern presidential campaign committee (1972).
In 1973 Chauncey founded and became the first Director of the Washington Office of the Presbyterian Church (US). After the two major Presbyterian Churches merged in 1983 to become the Presbyterian Church (USA), Chauncey continued to serve in the new denomination's Washington Office until his retirement in 1989. A monthly columnist for fifteen years for The Presbyterian Survey, the denomination's official magazine, he also wrote numerous articles for other denominations and ecumenical groups. His book, Decisions! Decisions!, an introduction to Christian ethics, was published by John Knox Press in 1972.
In 1974 Chauncey organized and for eight years served as the chairman of the Interreligious Taskforce on US Food Policy, a highly respected ecumenical lobby of 30 Protestant, Roman Catholic, and Jewish organizations working on US policies affecting global hunger and poverty. Beginning a decade later, he worked for five years as a member of the Washington Interreligious Staff Group on Central America, which opposed US policy in Central America; in the course of this work, he led three Presbyterian fact-finding delegations to Nicaragua and El Salvador. Health problems led him to retire in 1989.
Scope and Contents
Documenting the life and work of a 1952 graduate of the Yale Divinity School, the George A. Chauncey Papers illuminate many aspects of the civil rights movement and anti-Vietnam War movement at the local level, and they provide rich documentation of the bureaucratic, activist, and theological aspects of the progressive interreligious church lobby that developed in Washington, D.C., in the 1980s and 1990s.
Arrangement
I. Writings, Sermons, and Addresses
II. Documentation of Activities
III. Subject Files
IV. Related to Yale Divinity School
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia
VI. Audio-visual Material
Presbyterians; Civil rights -- Religious aspects -- Christianity; Chauncey, George A., 1927-
- Writings, Sermons, and Addresses, Series I
  - Undergraduate work
    - Thesis at Southwestern at Memphis College, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Parish ministry in Monticello, Arkansas
    - Sermon notes, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PCUS centenary evangelism campaign, Atlanta
    - Sermons and articles, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parish ministry in Danville, Kentucky
    - Articles and sermons, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and sermon notes, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sermons from binder, 1960-1965 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Given at First Presbyterian Church in Danville, Kentucky Includes Table of Contents with 4 headings: (1) Faith and Doubt, (2) The Gospel of God, (3) Life in the World, and (4) Church and Sacraments.
  - Civil rights/peace activism - Richmond/Washington years
    - Central America, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Christianity and politics, 1971-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Church responsibility, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Confidential journal: Account of Chauncey's trips to Mississippi and Alabama, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      This journal documents Chauncey's meetings with white pastors who had alienated their congregations by supporting the civil rights movement. It provides an intimate account of such struggles in Southern white churches. Includes sermons/Addresses: "Drafted by God," "The Role of the Church in a Time of National Tension," "A Strategy for the Church in Society."
    - Economics and faithfulness, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ethical issues (especially justice), 1972-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Evangelism lectures, no date (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Evangelism writings, ca. 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Evangelism course, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Faithfulness requirements, 1975-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Assembly report, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Global Economic Context in Which God Calls Us To Faithfulness, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Justice and worship, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Luke lectures, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Hunger and food policy, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Personal writings and the meaning of being a Christian, 1966-1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Public policy, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Social change, 1966-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Vietnam, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Washington, D.C. and Vancouver, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Watergate, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - What Faithfulness Requires in Today's Economic Situation, No date (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Witnessing community lectures, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous sermon notes, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sermons from binder: (1) Culture and Society, (2) Race, 1965-1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Sermons from binder: (3) Vietnam, (4) Reports and BCE [Board of Christian Education]., 1965-1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Topically arranged sermons
    - Advent (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Ascension (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Baptism (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Bible (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Christian Education (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Christmas (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Church and Its Mission (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
    - Confirmation (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Easter / Eastertide (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Encounter with Christ (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Faith / Doubt (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Freedom (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - God: Father, King (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Gospel (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Gratitude (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Holy Communion (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Holy Spirit / Trinity (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Jeremiah (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Lectures on Ethics (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Lent (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Life of Christ (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
    - Lord's Prayer (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Love for Neighbor (Service Corps) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Ministry of the Laity (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Nature of Christ (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Nature of Man / Image of God (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Notes on Mission and Race (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Old Testament Heroes (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Pentecost (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Politics (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Prayer (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Presbyterianism. Belief and Government (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Race Relations (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Salvation (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Sex, Marriage, Christian Home (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Social Ethics (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Social Issues (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Special Sermons and Talks (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Stewardship (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Teachings of Christ (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Ten Commandments: Law of God (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Three Lectures: People of God (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Vocation (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Work and worship (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Sermons arranged by title
    - A: "A Challenge About the Church" - "Ascriptions of Praise" (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - B-C: "Basic Connections I Bring to New York" - "Cross and Suffering" (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - D-F: "D. Daniel Dodson" - "Funeral Prayer" (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - G-H: "The Gift to the Church" - "The Humanity of God" (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - I-L: "Image of God" - "Lord, Show Us the Father" (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - M-P: "The Master of the Storm" - "Public Accommodations Workshop" (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - R-S: "Rediscovery of the Gospel" - "Sunday Worship" (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - T-Y: "The Task Prepared By God" - "The Year of the Lord" (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - No title (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Documentation of Activities, Series II
  - Parish Ministry
    - Brownsville, TN church documents and bulletins, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Brownsville, TN church correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Monticello, AR church documents and bulletins, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Monticello, AR church newsletters, 1954-1958 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Monticello, AR church correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Danville, KY church documents, bulletins, newspaper clippings, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Danville, KY church correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PCUS centenary evangelism campaigns
    - Documents, church bulletins, newsclippings, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Rev. Chauncey's notes and business cards, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - University of Mississippi incident
    An invitation to the Rev. Alvin Kershaw to speak at a Religious Emphasis week at the University was withdrawn because of Kershaw's support of the NAACP. Other participants, including Chauncey, withdrew in support of Kershaw. Ole Miss faculty resigned in protest.
    - Articles, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes pamphlets and propaganda regarding integration, segregation, and desegregation in the South
    - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Central High School integration, Little Rock, AR
    - Magazine articles, newspaper clippings re. school integration disputes, pamphlet: "The Editorial Position of the Arkansas Gazette in the Little Rock School Crisis", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Women's retreat, Presbyterian Church
    - Pamphlets,correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Richmond, VA - activities while Secretary of Division of Church and Society, Presbyterian Church Board of Christian Education
    - Anti-Vietnam War protests and speeches: Mobilization Committee Against the War in Vietnam documents and other committee materials, newspaper clippings, 1965-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters and correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Committee of Concerned Citizens material Mother's Day March in Charleston, SC, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - George McGovern presidential campaign
    - Campaign material and correspondence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Presbyterian Survey public policy column
    - Copies of Rev. Chauncey's column, 1974-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fan mail regarding the column, 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Interreligious Task Force on US Food Policy
    - Food policy agenda, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Statements and documents, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Statements and documents, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Statements and documents, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Statements and documents, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Statements and documents, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Statements and documents, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Statements and documents, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Washington Interreligious Staff Group on Central America
    - Mobilization for justice and peace - 1, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mobilization for justice and peace - 2, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Mobilization for justice and peace - 3, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mobilization for justice and peace articles, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Mobilization for justice and peace fund-raising materials, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Mobilization for justice and peace steering and program committees' materials, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lenten Witness and church services, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Documents - 1, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Documents - 2, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - PC USA position on Central America, 1978-1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Calls to action from the church, 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Pledge of Resistance, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Conflicting Views on the subject, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper articles documenting protest activities, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - History of the problems, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Current administration's position, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Articles exposing lies on the topic, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Nicaragua, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Contra aid, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - El Salvador, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Rev. Chauncey's notes and articles, 1982-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Central American map, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - McClurg Act, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - UPC Task Force on Homosexuality
    - Formal reports, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Policy statements and Rev. Chauncey's contributions, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - PCUS Council on Theology and Culture statements, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - PC and homosexuality materials, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, pamphlets, and other material, 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Washington Office of the Presbyterian Church
    - PCUS social and public policy statements, 1965-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - PCUS social and public policy statements, 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - PCUS social and public policy statements, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Copies of "Report to Presbyterians From Washington", 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Negative responses to Rev. Chauncey's invitation to be Presbyterian Advocates, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - General Washington documents and correspondence, 1978-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Reports on Rev. Chauncey's work from his and others' perspectives - 1, 1978-1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Reports on Rev. Chauncey's work from his and others' perspectives - 2, 1973-1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with and documents regarding Belle miller McMaster, 1970-1989 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - General Presbyterian material
    - Synod of S.C. 1972 meeting and correspondence (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Service bulletins outside parish ministry, 1977-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Presbyterians and Peacemaking, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Official Presbyterian Church publications, 1961-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Subject Files, Series III
  - Alphabetical sequence
    - American Society of Christian Ethics, 1971-1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Anger in the Bible notes, no date (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Baum, Gregory: Critical Theology, notes, no date (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Biblical justice notes and drafts, no date (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Black Theology material for CASM retreat, no date (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Brown, Robert McAfee, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Brueggemann, Walter A., 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Calhoun, Robert L., 1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Central America (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Chomsky, Noam, no date (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Christiansen, Drew, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Come, Arnold - Calvinist view, no date (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Commanger, no date (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - DuBoff - The new Economic Mythology, no date (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Economic justice, no date (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ethics - 1, no date (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Ethics - 2, no date (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Ethics and justice, no date (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ethical norms, no date (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Ethical policy, no date (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Fackenheim, Emil L., no date (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Faith and justice, no date (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Geyer, Alan (primarily), no date (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Gilkey, Langdon, no date (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Global justice, no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Goulet, Denis, no date (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Green, Barbara, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Gustafson, James M., no date (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Gustafson UTS lectures, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Guthrie and others, no date (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Haverwas, Stanley, no date (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Hehir, J. Bryan, no date (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Henriot, Peter J., 1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Henriot, Peter and Joe Holland, no date (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Hessel, D., no date (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Inclusive church language, no date (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Junkin, Edward Dixon and Julia Ann Junkin, no date (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kairos document, no date (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Kittlaus, Paul, no date (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Lara-Braud, Jorge, no date (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Liberation theology, no date (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, no date (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard - Christian Ethics in history, no date (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard - essays - 1, no date (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard - essays - 2, no date (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold -biography, obituary, etc., no date (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold - biographical articles, no date (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Oldham, J. H., no date (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Political task of the church, no date (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Potter, Ralph B., no date (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Public ethics, no date (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Race relations, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Rasmussen, Larry, no date (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Religion and politics - 1, no date (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Religion and politics - 2, no date (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Religion and politics - 3, no date (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Religious right, no date (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Ruether, Rosemary Radford, no date (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur Jr., no date (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Shaull, Richard, no date (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sider, Ronald J., no date (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Soelle, Dorothee, no date (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Stassen, Glen H., no date (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Stotts, Jack, no date (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Telford, George, no date (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Theology, miscellaneous, no date (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Wallis, Jim, no date (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Warehime, Hel M., no date (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - West, Charles C., no date (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Wilbanks, Dana, no date (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Wogaman, J. Philip, no date (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Worship, Christ and the arts, no date (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Collected articles and clippings
    This is a sampling of the many articles clipped and saved by Rev. Chauncey,.
    - Related to Christianity and culture, politics, theology
      - Including from Christianity and Crisis, The Christian Century, 1953-1979 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Including from Christianity and Crisis, The Christian Century, Worldview, 1980-1984 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Including from Christianity and Crisis, The Christian Century, The New Republic, 1985-1989 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Including from Christianity and Crisis, The Christian Century, 1990-1992, no date (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Related to homosexuality
      - Including from Commonweal, Psychology Today, Christian Century, Blueboy, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Including from The Advocate, Colorado Woman Digest, The Witness, Metro Community News, etc., 1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Including from The Advocate, Gay Community News, The Blade, Christianity and Crisis, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Including from The Advocate, Christian Century, Christianity in Crisis, etc., 1979-1993, no date (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Related to Presbyterian Church and social issues, theology
      - Including from Church and Society Opinion, The Presbyterian Journal, Washington Theology of Mission event, 1963-1978 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Including Rethinking Social Ministry, "Presbyterians and Economic Justice Issues...", Presbyterians and Peacemaking, 1980-1988 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Related to Yale Divinity School, Series IV
  - Classes and papers
    - Old Testament and New Testament term papers, 1950-1952 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Old Testament notes and papers, 1950-1952 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - History of Christian Doctrine notes, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Introduction to Theology notes and papers, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Protestant Theology since Schleiermacher notes, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Yale papers, 1950-1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Class of 1952 class letter books
    - 1956, 1962, 1965, 1972, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1981-1986 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1987-1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1991-1994 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1995-1998 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 2000 - February, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - November 2003 - 2006 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 2009-2011 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia
    - Reflection book, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series V
  - High school reunion booklet, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Danville, KY, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Certificates, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Church bulletins and programs (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
  - Personal notes, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Sabbatical #1, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Sabbatical #2, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Notes - "Some Learnings After 5 Years", 1974 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Personal notes from Washington, D.C. years, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Fan mail, 1966-1987 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Honorary degree, Rhodes College, Memphis, TN, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - One World magazine with his photograph, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Notes on "Marti", no date (Box 19, Folder 10)